Guide to the Ernst Toller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Published Works, 1917-1978; Series II; 6.3' (19 boxes)
  - Books and Plays
    - The Swallow-Book (Das Schwalbenbuch). English version by Ashley Dukes. London: Oxford University Press, Humphrey Milford, 1924. (Box 20)
    - Which World - Which Way? Travel Pictures from America and Russia. Authorized English version by Hermon Ould. London: Sampson Low, Marston & Co. Ltd., [1931]. (Box 20)
    - Ik Was een Duitscher. Geautoriseerde vertaling uit het Duitsch van Nico Rost. Amsterdam: Uitg. Mij Contact, 1934. (Box 21)
    - In de Boeien. Werk van Ernst Toller. Vertaling poezie van Margot Vos. Vertaling proza van Joan Timmer. Hilversum: Boekenfrienden Solidariteit, 1935. (Box 21)
    - Massa-Mensch. Een Stuk uit de Sociale Revolutie der 20e Eeuw. Vertaald door J.Jac. Thomson. Inleiding van W. Banning. Huis ter Heide: N.V. Uitgevers-Mij: "De Tijdstroom,", 1925. (Box 21)
    - Het Zwaluwenboek. Vertaald en Ingeleid door A. Mankes-Zernike. Huis ter Heide: N.V. Uitgevers-Mij. "De Tijdstroom,", 1928. (Box 21)
    - La Hirundlibro. El la germana lingvo tradukita de Helene Wolff, Kleve. Köln: Propra eldono. En komisio ce "Heroldo de Esperanto", 1924. (Box 21)
    - Le Livre de l'Hirondelle. Traduit de l'allemand par Alzir Hella et Olivier Bournac. Marseille: Les Cahiers du Sud, 1928 (Box 21)
    - Hinkemann. Tragedie. Traduite d'allemand par J.-P. Samson. Illustré de six dessins par Georg Grosz, Les Humbles Revue Littéraire des Primaires, XI, 1 (Jan. 1926): 1-93. (Box 21)
    - Hop la, Nous Vivous! Un Prologue et Cinq Actes. Adaptation francaise de Cesar Gattegno et Beatrice Perregaux. Paris: Les Éditeurs Francais Reunis, 1966. (Box 21)
    - Masses and Man. Gujarati translation. (Box 22)
    - Transfiguration. Gujarati translation. (Box 22)
    - Twelve plays in Russian translation. (electrostatic copies) Kulturne Posljedice Požara Raijhstaga. Govor u Londonskom Protoprocesu. Preveo Mirko Kus-Nikolajev. Zagreb: Nakladna Knjižara Epoha, 1933. (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Minor Works and Reprints
    - 1919-1973, undated (Box 24, Folder 74-79)
  - Oversize Box
    - Brokenbrow. Translated by Vera Mendel with drawings by Georg Grosz. London: Nonesuch Press, 1926. (Box 25, Folder 80)
    - Feuer aus den Kesseln, Historisches Schauspiel: Anhang: Historische Dokumente. Berlin: Oesterheld & Co., 1930. (Box 25, Folder 81)
- Works about Toller, 1922-1976; Series III; 7.5" (2 boxes)
  Series III is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Andersen, Francis P. "An Analytical Study of Techniques on Persuasion in the Plays of Ernst Toller." Ph.D. dissertation, University of Southern California, 1956. (Box 26, Folder 82)
  - Auden, W.H. "In Memory of Ernst Toller (d. May 1939)," typewritten poem (Box 26, Folder 83)
  - Droop, Fritz. Ernst Toller und seine Bühnenwerke. Eine Einführung. Mit selbstbiographsisehen Notizen des Bühnendichters. Die Wandlung, Masse Mensch, Die Maschinenstürmer, EugenHinkemann. Berlin-Leipzig: Franz Schneider, 1922. (Box 26, Folder 84)
  - Elsasser, Robert. "Ernst Toller and German Society: The Role of the Intellectual as Critic, 1914-1939." Ph.D. dissertation, Rutgers University, 1973. (Box 26, Folder 85-86)
  - Lieberman, Herman. Ernst Toller - Di Tragedye fun a zukhenden Gaist. New York: "Feder,", 1924. (Box 26, Folder 87)
  - Mierendorff, Marta."Beginnt das Spiel von neuem? Zum 30. Todestag Ernst Tollers." Frankfurter Rundshau, 117 (22. Mai 1969). (Box 26, Folder 88)
  - Mierendorff, Martha. "Ernst Toller zum 30. Todestag (1. Dezember 1893-1922. Mai 1939)." Die Mahnung, 9 (1. Mai 1969): 10-12. (Box 26, Folder 89)
  - Park, William MacFarlane. "Ernst Toller: The European Exile Years 1933-1936." Ph.D. dissertation, University of Colorado, 1976. (Box 26, Folder 90)
  - Pollack, Frederick. "Ernst Toller. A Play in One Act." Branford Lit, 1 (1964):31-66. (Box 26, Folder 91)
  - Rogers, Jacqueline Helen. "Ernst Toller's Prose Writings." Ph.D. dissertation, Yale University, 1972. (Box 27, Folder 92-93)
  - Spalek, John M. "Ernst Toller: The Need for a New Estimate. The German Quarterly, XXXIX, 4 (Nov. 1966): 581-598. (Box 27, Folder 94)
  - Spalek, John M. und Frühwald, Wolfgang. "Ernst Toller's Amerikanische Vortragsreise 1936/1937." Literaturwissenschaftliches Jahrbuch. (1965): 267-311. (Box 27, Folder 95)
  - Spalek, John M. und Fruhwald, Wolfgang. Der Fall Toller: Kommentar und Materialen, Munchen: Carl Hanser, 1979. (Box 27, Folder 96)
  - Spalek, John M. "Der Nachless Ernst Tollers." Literatutwissenschaftliches Jahrbuch. (1965): 251-266. (Box 27, Folder 97)
  - Wolff, Charlotte. "Walter Wicclair ehrt Ernst Toller." Mitteilungsblatt, XXIII, 7 (July 1969). (Box 27, Folder 98)
- Additional Material, 1928; Accession 1991-M-060; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1991 Apr
  Received from: Bert Kasties, 1991 Feb 11
  - Bourgeois Bleibt Bourgeois, von Walter Hasenclever and Ernst Toller, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional Material, 1933; Accession 2012-M-011
  - Five postcards, letters, and telegrams written or received by Ernst Toller., 1933 (Box 1)